Guide to the Radio Haiti Papers, circa 1934-2003, bulk 1968-2003 RL.11499
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Oversized, Photos and AV materials, circa 1934-2004
  - AV materials, 1980-2001
    - "This Week in South Florida" with Jean Dominique and Ian Martin, 1994-06-19 (Box 197)
      Michael Putney of This Week In South Florida interviews Jean Dominique and British human rights advocate Ian Martin of MICIVIH about whether economic sanctions will be enough to force the military regime from power or whether military intervention will be necessary. Dominique says that the phone call option is always there  the US government could simply phone General Cédras and tell him to leave. Martin describes the Haitian army as a force of internal repression that was created by the United States. They discuss the Governors Island accord and the US governments decision to withdraw the USS Harlan County from Haitian waters after armed thugs affiliated with the military regime demonstrated at the docks.
    - KRS-One on H.E.A.L. (Human Education Against Lies), circa 1994 (Box 197)
      Various clips of hip-hop artist KRS-One, released by the organization he co-founded, H.E.A.L. (Human Education Against Lies). He discusses the importance of intellect over memory, colonial exploitation of Africa, the "Stop the Violence" movement, and the song "Self Destruction." Undated, early 1990s.
    - Jonathan Demme on Jean Dominique's assassination, Charlie Rose, 2000-04-07 (Box 197)
      Four days after Jean Dominique's assassination, Jonathan Demme speaks to Charlie Rose about Dominique's life and death. Demme declares that it is not known who killed Dominique, but the United States is partly responsible for his death due to their repeated efforts to undermine democracy in Haiti. Includes a clip of Dominique on Charlie Rose's show in 1994.
    - Vodou: Haiti's Eternal Promise (demo tape), Kartemquin Films, Undated; circa 1990s (Box 197)
      Demo tape for a film called "Vodou: Haiti's Eternal Promise." Narrated by scholar William Balan-Gaubert, who discusses Lakou Souvenance, death rituals and the "peyi san chapo," among other topics. The full film will explore the lives of Esther, an eleven-year-old girl who grew up in Lakou Souvenance and who is a Vodou drummer, and the Haitian singer Marjorie Beaubrun, who grew up Protestant and became a Vodou adherent later in life.
    - CBS news report on Yves Volel's assassination, 1987-10 (Box 197)
      Victoria Corderi reports from Port-au-Prince on the assassination of presidential candidate Yves Volel. Jean Dominique describes violence by Macoutes that seek to intimidate people so they do not vote in the 29 November 1987 elections.
    - NBC news report on democratization of Haiti and the return of Jean Dominique, 1986 (Box 197)
      John Hart reports from Haiti on the return of Jean Dominique in March 1986. Includes footage of Dominique arriving at the airport in Port-au-Prince. Dominique describes how broadcasting in Haitian Creole, with its "mmhmmms" and other nonverbal utterances, allowed people to express their beliefs without stating them: in one mmmhmm, "there is three Macoutes involved." Dominique explains the exploitation of the Haitian poor by the Macoutes and the chefs de section, and how the dechoukaj of Macoute elements from the government must not also destroy the good parts of the government. Also includes a report from Parisse, in the Nord-Est, where people describe their poverty and their hopes for democracy. (Tape also includes a brief report on Radio Martí, which broadcasts news from the US to Cuba; President Ronald Reagan declares, "Cuba sí, Castro no." Also includes what appears to be raw footage of the aftermath of a collision between a bus and a car on I-95 in Miami.)